<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning. | Abdallah Bashir</title>
    <link>https://abdallah197.github.io/tag/machine-learning./</link>
      <atom:link href="https://abdallah197.github.io/tag/machine-learning./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine Learning.</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 23:21:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://abdallah197.github.io/images/icon_huf6aa2282c16144427e775bed4082022e_60978_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Machine Learning.</title>
      <link>https://abdallah197.github.io/tag/machine-learning./</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offinsive tweets classification</title>
      <link>https://abdallah197.github.io/project/twitter-offinsive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 23:17:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abdallah197.github.io/project/twitter-offinsive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;school-assignment&#34;&gt;School Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-description&#34;&gt;Task Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task to be completed within this project is to develop and evaluate a system that processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a single tweet and decides whether or not the tweet contains offensive language. This task&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;could be tackled as a binary text classification problem. To this end,  a dataset of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tweets annotated for offensiveness is provided in the repo. The files “train.tsv” and “dev.tsv” all have the same format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second column (text) contains the text of a tweet, the first column (label) contains an&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;offensiveness label:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(NOT) Not Offensive - This post does not contain offense or profanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(OFF) Offensive - This post contains offensive language or a targeted (veiled or direct)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;offense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below shows a few examples of tweets that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;have been annotated as offensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 @USER Liberals are all Kookoo !!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 @USER @USER Most stupid tweet yet&amp;hellip;and yes&amp;hellip;its a libtard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 @USER I bet the first ones she calls when she is being robbed is those&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;very same police . People are freaking stupid &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 @USER @USER Go home you’re drunk!!! @USER #MAGA #Trump2020 URL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;baseline-classifier&#34;&gt;Baseline Classifier&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naive bayes and svm classifiers were used as models.

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abdallah197/Offensive-Language-Detection-on-Twitter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Natural Language Understanding for Arabic Dialogue Systems</title>
      <link>https://abdallah197.github.io/project/nlu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 23:16:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abdallah197.github.io/project/nlu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Understanding (NLU) is considered a core component in implementing dialogue systems. NLU has been greatly enhanced by deep learning techniques such as word embeddings and deep neural network architectures, but current NLP methods for Arabic language dialogue action classification or semantic decoding is mostly based on handcrafted rule-based systems and methods that use feature engineering, but without the benefit of any form of distributed representation of words. This paper presents an approach to use deep learning techniques for text classification and Named Entity Recognition for the domain of home automation in Arabic. To this end, we present an NLU module that can further be integrated with Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR), a Dialogue Manager (DM) and a Natural Language Generator (NLG) module to build a fully working dialogue system. The paper further describes our process of collecting and annotating the data, structuring the intent classifier and entity extractor models, and finally the evaluation of these methods on different benchmarks.

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abdallah197/NLU--ArabicDialogueSystems&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to the repo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
